# **Alamin Rahman**

Address: Romford, London

Mobile: 07539852381 Email: alamin7846@gmail.com

Portfolio: alaminrahman.co.uk

#### **Personal Profile**

Combining experience in customer service and business operations. I offer versatility and reliability. I started an IT bootcamp and found a real passion for web development. As you can see through my enrolment in a rigorous 3-month Software Development Skills Bootcamp with Just IT and ongoing self-study on platforms like Udemy and YouTube. This commitment reflects my dedication and eagerness to expand my knowledge in this field, aligning with my goal of becoming a skilled Junior Software Developer. I aim to create solutions that solve problems, continually learning and growing in coding and expand my horizons

## **Core Skills**

Call Handling

Customer Service

Payment Processing

• Market Research

Team Leading

Microsoft Excel

- Organisational
- Time management
- Content Creation

#### **IT Skills**

Web Technology: HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript Technology: Git | GitHub

# **Employment History**

## India Royal - Waiter/Manager

(Jun 2015 - Aug 2023)

- Waiter (2015-2020), Manager (2020-2023)
- Demonstrated flexibility and adaptability by taking on more responsibilities as manager such as, managing the business, dealing with complaints, paying wages, ordering stock, etc.
- Used time management and organisation to help with processing customer orders to help keep the flow moving
- Provided excellent customer service skills by handling customer requests and complaints in a prompt manner during busy hours.
- Dealt with inventory and end of day takings.

# Personalise Me Ltd - Social Media Manager

(Oct 2021 - March 2022)

- Demonstrated strong organisational and time management skills by handling projects and deadlines within set period.
- Effectively utilised market research and content creation to help enhance social media presence and gain new traffic to the page.
- Collaborated with colleagues to help create and manage content calendar and social media pages as well as run an e-commerce business through Shopify
- Helped improve client brand identities and content strategies by reviewing and providing feedback to social media pages.
- Regularly posted and updated social media posts

# **Lazard Plumbing - Apprentice Plumber**

(Sep 2019 - March 2020)

- Addressed customer inquiries through written and verbal communication while assisting colleagues.
- Worked effectively in a team environment and individually when needed.

• Demonstrated flexibility and adaptability while utilising various tools and equipment which helped with troubleshooting and problem-solving where needed.

# **Education and IT Training**

## **Click Start London - Digital Skills Training**

(Nov 2023 - Dec 2023)

- Click Start is a programme based around essential digital skills relating to how to collect, manage and utilise data
- Fundamentals of Digital Marketing and Microsoft Office Specialist in Excel qualification
- Tech Adoption Lab paired with a Small/Medium Employer (SME) supporting the SME to adopt a new technology. The aim is to supplement classroom training with real business examples and learn the consultative skills that enable me to really embed my tech skills and develop the skills for work.

# **Just IT Training - Software Development Bootcamp**

(June 2023 - Sep 2023)

 A twelve-week intensive bootcamp covering the fundamentals of Web and Software development such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL and Python

# **Canterbury College - Diploma**

(Sep 2017 - May 2019)

• Plumbing diploma level 2 & 3

# **Darul Uloom London - GCSE's and Diploma**

(Jan 2011 - Oct 2016)

• Completed GCSE's and Level 2 Team Leading Diploma

## **Coding Projects**

# JavaScript:

• Created a <u>weather app</u>, <u>text to speech app</u> and a <u>quiz game</u>.

# Python and MySQL:

Created a movie database with CRUD functionality.

#### Ongoing:

• Trying to create a takeaway website to help update a small businesses current website

#### **Interests**

Hobbies: Gaming | Gym | Reading | Continuous learning | Movies/TV

#### **Additional Info:**

- I have a full driving licence
- I speak both English and Bengali

References available upon request